Guide to the NYU Abu Dhabi Covid-19 Archive AD.RG.030.2
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- NYUAD Community Participatory Covid Archive, 2021-2022; 252 Megabytes comprised of 71 items.
  - Digital Submissions
    - Contreras, Janine. J9 in 2020 [video], 2018-2020; Submission 9 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_009)
      One day, I realized I could use the footage I've accumulated over the past few years (including pre-COVID and COVID times) and compile them as 1-second clips with a day-in-the-life arc. This artistic choice represents how unbelievably quick life in 2020 has gone by. It also contrasts my pre-COVID and COVID days, as well as my life back in the Philippines last Fall 2020 and my life on campus this Spring 2021. It shows how much has changed in my life: how we used to go on desert trips and even zoos for a class excursion, being able to attend an in-person commencement instead of a virtual one, taking college classes in my high school bedroom, transitioning from using the Fitness Center to floor lounges to my house's living room, and so much more.
      Lastly, this video is a summation of the different dimensions to my identity, what and who I value most in life, and the dichotomy between Janine at home and NYUAD- something akin to the experience of every other NYUAD student.
      I am submitting a hybrid of a 1-second-video compilation and the typical 'day in a life' vlog. All video clips were taken by me in the past 3 years (ie. from 2018-present), at home in Bulacan, Philippines when I studied remotely last semester, as well as on-campus and in other places in the UAE. It includes videos of my family and friends.
    - Lee, Theodore. First RTC Steering Committee [Photos], May 2020; Submission 12 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_012)
      University role: Senior Director, Integrated Solutions Group Return to Campus Role: Program Manager, Return To Campus
      First RTC Steering Committee Zoom Meeting May 27, 2020
      Participants (in zoom screen order) Jessica Sederquist Theodore Lee Martin Klimke Lily Burns-Hernandez Sehamuddin Galadari Carol Brandt Fabio Piano Peter Christensen Mariet Westermann Kyle Farley
    - Anonymous. The world runs better on vaccines [screenshot], August, 2020 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_022)
      A screenshot of the green pass used in the UAE to access public and private facilities, travel between Emirates, and to verify vaccination status.
      To imagine a world in perpetual lockdown was not an option for me. I wanted people to have the option to connect other than the online space. The development of the various Covid vaccines provided some of the best options to work toward a healthier population. This vaccine trial was a step to getting things reopened. My biggest concern is that a worldwide pandemic will be forgotten in just a few years when there is so much more to be learned from it.
    - Chavele Dastamani, Sofia. Student Model Arab League Conference Moves to Zoom [Photos], November 2020; Submission 10 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_010)
      I am an Engineering student and serve as the President of the Student Interest Group Model Arab League at NYU Abu Dhabi.
      Battling varying timezones, the very different locations of all our SIG members and student leaders, regulations prohibiting more than 3 of us to sit in the same room, very low application numbers (thanks to Zoom fatigue), arriving at a virtual format for our Model Arab League conference was not an easy task. Organized by NYUAD students, for NYUAD students, we continued the legacy of the first Model Arab League conference in GCC in a fully remote format, with our E-board working across London and Abu Dhabi to put the event together. Despite over 10 hours spent on Zoom, and a fully remote format, our delegates remained engaged and we passed two resolutions (working papers outlining solutions proposed by the committee). The team won over 5 awards and moved on to participate in more remote conferences across the United States for the rest of the 2021 season!
      These are screenshots/group pictures of a session at the 3rd annual Fall internal Model Arab League Conference at NYU Abu Dhabi, held on November 20-21, for the very first time on Zoom. Poster advertising the remote event on social media. This conference is an opportunity for NYUAD students to gather together and discuss topics of regional and international importance, typically held on campus every Fall, was moved to Zoom during COVID-19, with delegates dialing in from the UK, Greece, Poland, Abu Dhabi, and beyond.
    - Lee, Ivory. 'Shared Stories' Journaling Project, Spring 2021; Submission 13 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_013)
      I worked as a student assistant with Wayne from the Wellness Department on making the Journaling Project happen.
      Every week for four weeks, five 'Shared Stories' journals were scattered around campus. Each journal had a different prompt, making 20 prompts in total. In order to take part in the project, students and community members had to find the journal somewhere on campus, open it up, and scan the QR code in the journal. Each week, clues were given as to where the journals are. The QR code led to a Google Form detailing instructions and additional information about the project, as well as the prompt pertaining to that journal. Participants could then choose to submit a response anonymously or with their name. Once a response was submitted, we checked the response for safety and published it onto the Website on the corresponding page with the prompt. The Website allows for all to see all prompts that we have had and read all responses that have been approved. For each prompt, one response was chosen to win a prize.
      Duration: 4 weeks; 1 week at a time
      Project mission: In recent times, we have found it increasingly harder to connect with one another and to take time to reflect. With the 'Shared Stories' project, we hope to bring the NYUAD community together by sharing some stories and experiences that have shaped us and made us who we are, individually and collectively, today. The project also served as an incentive to encourage community members to be more active and to search for the journals around campus.
      Project website: https://sites.google.com/nyu.edu/wellness-journaling-project/home
    - Hamilton, Shona. Through the eyes of a child [poetry], Summer 2021; Submission 16 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_016)
      I have only recently joined the University as EA to Kyle Farley and Student Affairs Office Manager
      A poem written about the Pandemic (more specifically lock down) through the eyes of a child.
      I have a daughter who is too little to understand the pandemic and how our lives were turned upside down. During lock down my husband had I had every emotion taking hold from anxiety / stress / worry etc but we also hugely valued the family time we were having. We did however notice that our daughter was blissfully unaware of what was happening and was just delighted to be spending so much time with mummy and daddy and playing on the balcony etc.
    - Gleason, Nancy. The complex world of PCR testing in schools [screenshot], September 2021; Submission 21 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_021)
      I am a faculty member in the political science department and I am the Director of the Hilary Ballon Center for Teaching and Learning. I am entering my third year at NYUAD, so I joined just 6 months before the pandemic started.
      Text on PCR testing from a K-12 school in Abu Dhabi
      The text message details the complex world of PCR testing that NYUAD faculty of school age children were dealing with 18 months into the pandemic. As the rules on vaccinations and testing change regularly, this is a glimpse at the coordination it requires to manage our personal lives while working at NYUAD.
    - Kata, Lauren. UAE Al Hosn App Green and Red [screenshots], May 2022 (Box E-records, Folder AD_RG_030_023)
      Two years into the pandemic, I finally got Covid, after leaving the UAE and traveling to Spain for a spring holiday during the end of April/beginning of May, 2022. It felt like a really bad flu, I was shivering with a fever for days and couldn't stop coughing. I learned I had Covid because I was tested upon arrival at the airport. After months and months of only knowing the "green" or the "grey" colors of the Al Hosn app, I finally saw the "red," indicating I tested positive. These screenshots show me at red and then at green, and include the explanation and instructions about what I was to do after testing positive, including the procedure of quarantining. I quarantined at home for 10 days, testing myself with at-home Covid tests until I no longer was positive. I then went for an official test at the local testing center at Galleria Mall, which led to me going back to the green. I appreciated the efforts of the UAE government to create a mechanism to efficiently track Covid cases and provide a way for the population to move through the experience of contracting the virus in an honest and responsible way. While some may have found it to be an inconvenience, I appreciated it and was happy to follow protocols, which were created to help keep our communities as safe as possible.
      Lauren Kata is a member of the academic librarian team in Archives and Special Collections and works with the NYUAD University Archives. She is the archivist who processed this Covid Archive.